A Guide to the E. B. Norris Papers, 1928-1955, n.d.
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
E. B. Norris Papers, 1928-1955, n.d.
Special Collections, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms1981-103
1.5 cu. ft. 1 box; 1 folder
E.B. Norris was Dean of Engineering at VPI from 1928-1952, and his papers include reports concerning the agriculture and engineering departments, reports on individual development, newspaper clippings, catalogues, brochures, and correspondence, particularly regarding then-President Burruss.
Norris, Earle B., (Earle Bertram), 1882-1966
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
The E. B. Norris Papers was acquired prior to 1981.
Biographical Note
Earle Bertram Norris was born in 1882 in New York. He attended Pennsylvania State College and graduated in 1904. He was a captain in World War I and received a Purple Heart. He became a professor at Virginia Tech in 1928, and was the Dean of Engineering from 1928-1953. The engineering school grew under his leadership. He died in 1966. Norris Hall on Virginia Tech's campus was named after him.
Sources:
VT Magazine
Norris Hall
Scope and Content
E.B. Norris was Dean of Engineering at VPI from 1928-1952, and his papers include reports concerning the agriculture and engineering departments, reports on individual development, newspaper clippings, catalogues, brochures, and correspondence, particularly regarding then-President Burruss. The majority of the collection is Dr. Norris's correspondences. The collection also includes advertisements he received to purchase different classroom equipment. There are also publications he received about engineering, and various reports about engineering. There are also newspapers and a blueprint.
Arrangement
The E.B. Norris Papers are arranged alphabetically by material type.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Faculty; Science and Technology; University Archives; University History; Virginia Agricultural and Mechanical College and Polytechnic Institute; Virginia Polytechnic Institute
Contents List
- Advertisements (4 folders), n.d. (Box-folder 1-1 to 1-4)
- Center of Aeronautical Engineering Instruction and Research, 1928-1929 (Box-folder 1-5)
- Commencement Programs, June 1929,1930 (Box-folder 1-6)
- Correspondence (President Burruss 1929), 1929 (Box-folder 1-7)
- Correspondence (President Burruss 1930), 1930 (Box-folder 1-8)
- Correspondence, February-April 1937 (Box-folder 1-9)
- Correspondence, June-July 1937 (Box-folder 1-10)
- Correspondence, August-September 1937 (Box-folder 1-11)
- Correspondence, October-December 1937 (Box-folder 1-12)
- Correspondence, January-March 1938 (Box-folder 1-13)
- Correspondence, April-May 1938 (Box-folder 1-14)
- Correspondence, June-December 1938 (Box-folder 1-15)
- Correspondence, 1939 (Box-folder 1-16)
- Correspondence, 1947-1953 (Box-folder 1-17)
- Engineering Extension Division, 1929-1930 (Box-folder 1-18)
- Event Programs, 1938 (Box-folder 1-19)
- Nautical School, 1939 (Box-folder 1-20)
- Nautical School, 1940 (Box-folder 1-21)
- Nautical School, 1941-1942 (Box-folder 1-22)
- Newspaper Clippings, 1938-1939 (Box-folder 1-23)
- Newspapers and Blueprint (Folder 1)
- Publications, 1930-1950 (Box-folder 1-24)
- Publications, 1951-1953, n.d. (Box-folder 1-25)
- Reports (3 folders), 1929-1955, n.d. (Box-folder 1-26 to 1- 28)
- Sample Exam, 1946 (Box-folder 1-29)